George Heinold Papers
© 2002 University of Connecticut
- Series III: Articles and Manuscripts, 1944-1982
  - Subseries B: Undated Articles and Manuscripts, undated
    - "Surfcraft for Sandy Shores", undated (Box 6:253)
    - "Swordsman of the Seas", undated (Box 6:254)
    - "Techniques for Sea-Run Trout", undated (Box 6:255)
    - "Those Brash and Brazen Bermudas", undated (Box 6:256)
    - "A 1001 Miles of Bluefish", undated (Box 6:257)
    - "Timberdoodle Dandy", undated (Box 6:258)
    - "Time for Snapper Blues", undated (Box 6:259)
    - "Torpedo with Teeth", undated (Box 6:260)
    - "Turkeys in Connecticut", undated (Box 6:261)
    - "Two Weeks of Tarpon", undated (Box 6:262)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 6:263)
    - "The Wariest Brown Trout of All", undated (Box 6:264)
    - "Yankee Squidder on the Pacific", undated (Box 6:265)
    - "A Wary Waterfowl", undated (Box 6:266)
    - Woodchucks, undated (Box 6:267)
    - "Yankee Lion", undated (Box 6:268)
    - "Yankee Squidder on the Pacific", undated (Box 6:269)
    - Proposed Book on Salt-Water Fishing Manuscript, ca. 1974 (Box 6:270)
  - Subseries C: "Salt Water Articles, 1957-1974
    - "How to Spin Drift", 1957 May (Box 7:271)
    - "To Catch Salmon", 1957 Sep (Box 7:272)
    - "Drums as Game Fish", ca. 1957 (Box 7:273)
    - Untitled, 1966 May (Box 7:274)
    - Untitled, 1967 Mar 3 (Box 7:275)
    - Untitled, 1967 Mar 12 (Box 7:276)
    - Eastern Shore, 1967 Mar 29 (Box 7:277)
    - Untitled, ca. 1967 Mar (Box 7:278)
    - Untitled, 1967 Apr 8 (Box 7:279)
    - Untitled, 1967 May 27 (Box 7:280)
    - Untitled, 1967 May 27 (Box 7:281)
    - Untitled, 1967 Jul 24 (Box 7:282)
    - Untitled, 1967 Sep 7 (Box 7:283)
    - Wire Lining, 1967 Oct 4 (Box 7:284)
    - Untitled, undated, 1967 (Box 7:285)
    - Untitled, ca. 1967 (Box 7:286)
    - Untitled, ca. 1967 (Box 7:287)
    - Plugs, 1968 Jan 18 (Box 7:288)
    - Stripers, 1968 Jan 18 (Box 7:289)
    - Jigs, 1968 Jun 1 (Box 7:290)
    - Untitled, 1968 Jun 22 (Box 7:291)
    - Untitled, 1968 Jul 28 (Box 7:292)
    - Popham Beach Bass, 1968 Sep 10 (Box 7:293)
    - Mackerel, 1968 Nov 22 (Box 7:294)
    - S/W Plugs, 1969 Jan 2 (Box 7:295)
    - Casting Technique, 1969 Jan 2 (Box 7:296)
    - Playing Fish, 1969 Jan 29 (Box 7:297)
    - Sailfish, 1969 Jan 29 (Box 7:298)
    - Live-Lining, 1969 Jun 9 (Box 7:299)
    - Stripers: "Bridge Fishing", 1969 Jul 16 (Box 7:300)
    - Untitled, 1969 Oct 24 (Box 7:301)
    - Jetty Fishing, 1969 Nov 15 (Box 7:302)
    - Northern Whiting, 1969 Dec 29 (Box 7:303)
    - Untitled, ca. 1969-1970 (Box 7:304)
    - Bottom Fishing, 1970 Apr 12 (Box 7:305)
    - Untitled, 1970 May 17 (Box 7:306)
    - Cod, 1970 Aug 31 (Box 7:307)
    - Worm Tail Jug, 1970 Sep 8 (Box 7:308)
    - Snook, 1970 Sep 20 (Box 7:309)
    - Barracuda, 1970 Oct 1 (Box 7:310)
    - Blues on Fly Rod, 1970 Nov 28 (Box 7:311)
    - Untitled, 1971 Mar 8 (Box 7:312)
    - Untitled, 1971 Mar 26 (Box 7:313)
    - Blues on Fly Rod, 1971 Apr 7 (Box 7:314)
    - Surf Safety, 1971 May 10 (Box 7:315)
    - Weakfish, 1971 May 10 (Box 7:316)
    - Landing Fish, 1971 Aug 29 (Box 7:317)
    - Pompano, 1971 Aug 22 (Box 7:318)
    - Maine Blues, 1971 Oct 6 (Box 7:319)
    - Untitled, 1971 Dec 1 (Box 7:320)
    - Whiting and Spot, 1971 Dec 27 (Box 7:321)
    - Snapper Blues, 1972 Mar 13 (Box 8:322)
    - Untitled, 1972 May 25 (Box 8:323)
    - Black Drum, 1972 Jun 19 (Box 8:324)
    - Cobia, 1972 Jun 27 (Box 8:325)
    - Deep-Running Plug, 1972 Dec 19 (Box 8:326)
    - Untitled, ca. 1972-1973 (Box 8:327)
    - Untitled, 1973 Jan 29 (Box 8:328)
    - Untitled, 1973 Feb 23 (Box 8:329)
    - "Underwater Ferret Rigs", 1973 ca. Jan-Mar (Box 8:330)
    - Untitled, 1973 Apr 5 (Box 8:331)
    - Mako, 1973 May 1 (Box 8:332)
    - "South Jersey's Jumbo Weakfish", 1973 Jul 13 (Box 8:333)
    - "Doormats of the Old Dominion", 1973 Nov 15 (Box 8:334)
    - "Bountiful Bottoms", 1974 Jun 14 (Box 8:335)
    - "Light Tackle Techniques", 1974 Dec 17 (Box 8:336)
    - "No Sport for Sissies", undated, 1974 (Box 8:337)
    - Untitled, undated, 1974 (Box 8:338)
    - Untitled, undated, 1974 (Box 8:339)
    - Bluefin Tuna, undated (Box 8:340)
    - "First Aid for Fisherman", undated (Box 8:341)
    - "Frostbite Codding", undated (Box 8:342)
    - "The Magnificent Marlin", undated (Box 8:343)
    - Mako Sharks, undated (Box 8:344)
    - "Presents That Please", undated (Box 8:345)
    - "Reading the Surf", undated (Box 8:346)
    - "Swinging Surfmen of the South", undated (Box 8:347)
    - "Tackle Maintenance Now", undated (Box 8:348)
    - Tautog, undated (Box 8:349)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 8:350)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 8:351)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 8:352)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 8:353)
    - "The Wonderful Wahoo", undated (Box 8:354)
  - Subseries D: Articles about Heinold, 1956-1977
    - "George Heinold's Lost Wildlife Sanctuary," New Haven Register, 1956 Jul 29 (Box 8:355)
    - "A writer on nature's trail," Branford Review, 1977 May 5 (Box 8:356)
- Series IV: Photographs, undated, ca. 1955-1979
  - Subseries A: Heinold Family Photographs, undated
    - Heinold Family, undated (Box 9:357)
  - Subseries B: Dated Photographs, ca. 1955-1975
    - Photographs, ca. 1955 - 1966 Oct (Box 9:358)
    - Rhode Island Surf, Bob Maxted, Striper and Blue, 1966 Oct (Box 9:359)
    - Virginia Channel Bass, 1966 Oct (Box 9:360)
    - Rhode Island Surf and Pier, Including Big Striper and Wardens Stocking, 1967 May (Box 9:361)
    - Photographs, 1967 Jun (Box 9:362)
    - Chesapeake Stripers, 1967 Jun (Box 9:363)
    - New Hampshire Mackerel, Saco River Bass, 1967 Jun (Box 9:364)
    - Nova Scotia Flounder, 1967 Jun (Box 9:365)
    - Photographs, 1967 Sep (Box 9:366)
    - Photographs, undated, 1967 - 1968 Aug (Box 9:367)
    - Chesapeake, 1968 Aug (Box 9:368)
    - Big Cod, 1968 sep 2 (Box 9:369)
    - Caturo Boat "Joka," Tuna, 1968 Sep (Box 9:370)
    - Photographs Set #1, 1968 Sep (Box 9:371)
    - Photographs Set #2, 1968 Sep (Box 9:372)
    - Codfish, Dutton Playing Shark, 1967-1968 (Box 9:373)
    - Photographs, undated, 1968 - 1969 Oct (Box 9:374)
    - Photographs, undated, 1969 Nov - 1970 Nov (Box 9:375)
    - Photographs, undated, 1970 Nov (Box 9:376)
    - Photographs, undated, 1970 Dec (Box 9:377)
    - "U Saat", undated, 1970 (Box 9:378)
    - Photographs, undated, 1970-1972 Oct (Box 9:379)
    - Photographs, 1972 Nov - 1973 Jul (Box 10:380)
    - Photographs, 1973 Aug-Nov (Box 10:381)
    - Beavertail Surf and Photos of Bass and Blues, 1973 Dec (Box 10:382)
    - Photographs, 1972-1973 (Box 10:383)
    - Photographs, 1974 Jan-Aug (Box 10:384)
    - Bluefishing, 1974 Oct (Box 10:385)
    - Photographs, 1975 (Box 10:386)
  - Subseries C: Subject Photographs, undated
    - Subject Photographs, A - Bi, undated (Box 11:387)
    - Photographs, Bluefish, undated (Box 11:388)
    - Subject Photographs, Bluefish, undated (Box 11:389)
    - Photographs, Bluefish, undated (Box 11:390)
    - Subject Photographs, Bluefish, undated (Box 11:391)
    - Subject Photographs, H - Mo, undated (Box 11:392)
    - Subject Photographs, Myrtle Beach: Claude Rogers and Axe Hornoff, undated (Box 11:393)
    - Subject Photographs, N - R, undated (Box 12:394)
    - Subject Photographs, S - Sh, undated (Box 12:395)
    - Subject Photographs, Shad--Connecticut, undated (Box 12:396)
    - Photographs, Stripers, undated (Box 12:397)
    - Photographs, Su, undated (Box 12:398)
    - Photographs, T - Z, undated (Box 12:399)
  - Subseries D: Printed Photographs, 1965-1979
    - "Blitzes in Blue," Outdoor Life, 1965 Aug (Box 13:400)
    - "Bottom Fishing in the Gulf," Outdoor Life, 1966 Feb (Box 13:401)
    - "Snow Hunt for Stew," Outdoor Life, 1966 Sep (Box 13:402)
    - "Plugs for the Salt," Outdoor Life, 1966 Oct (Box 13:403)
    - "Let's Go Ice Fishing", 1970 May (Box 13:404)
    - "Let's Go Ice Fishing", 1970 May (Box 13:405)
    - "Cobia Inshore Big Game", 1973 Jun (Box 13:406)
    - "Bottom Bounty", 1973 Jul 5 (Box 13:407)
    - "Pollock on Top," Outdoor Life, 1973 Jul (Box 13:408)
    - "Yellowtail Blitz," Outdoor Life, 1973 Aug (Box 13:409)
    - "Bathing Blues in the Surf," Outdoor Life, 1973 Nov (Box 14:410)
    - "Early Season Fluke," Outdoor Life, 1973 Nov (Box 14:411)
    - "Bountiful Bottoms", 1974 Jun 14 (Box 14:412)
    - "Cows in the Surf", 1974 Sep (Box 14:413)
    - "Bounty on the Bottom," Outdoor Life, 1974 Oct (Box 14:414)
    - "Wahoo," Outdoor Life, 1974 Dec (Box 14:415)
    - Cover Photo, Delaware Salt Water Fisherman, 1974 (Box 14:416)
    - "Frostbite Cod," Outdoor Life, 1975 Feb (Box 14:417)
    - "Samson of the Surf", 1975 Oct 8 (Box 14:418)
    - "Boat Fishing the Atlantic," Outdoor Life, 1976 Aug (Box 14:419)
    - "2002 Miles of Striped Bass", 1979 Jan 15 (Box 14:420)
    - "Blue Bombers, undated (Box 14:421)
    - "1001 Miles of Bluefish", undated (Box 14:422)
    - "Snapper Blues", undated (Box 14:423)
    - "Time for Snapper Blues", undated (Box 14:424)
    - "Wire Line Fishing," Outdoor Life, undated (Box 14:425)
    - "Salt Water:" Blue Tuna, undated (Box 14:426)
    - "Salt Water:" Hatteras Pawfish, undated (Box 14:427)
    - "Salt Water: Popping for Stripers", undated (Box 14:428)
    - "Salt Water", undated (Box 14:429)
  - Subseries E: Press Photographs, 1971
    - Dolphin, 1971 (Box 15:430)
    - Bahamas Fishing Trip by Bahamas News Bureau Photos, undated (Box 15:431)
    - Delaware Blues, undated (Box 15:432)
    - Mississippi, undated (Box 15:433)
    - Mostly Florida, undated (Box 15:434)
  - Subseries F: Negatives, 1965-1979
    - Heinold Family, undated (Box 16:435)
    - Dated Photographs, 1965-1973 (Box 16:436)
    - Subject Photographs, undated (Box 16:437)
    - Subject Photographs-Bluefish, undated (Box 16:438)
    - Subject Photographs-Stripers, undated (Box 16:439)
    - Published Photographs, 1966-1979 (Box 16:440)
    - Published Photographs, undated (Box 16:441)
    - Rolled Negatives-"Hatteras Surf" and Untitled, undated (Box 16:442)